A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s charitable gifts are estimated to have totaled $537 million. Combined with his father's charitable contributions of $540 million, his donations brought the total philanthropic work of the first two generations of the Rockefeller fortune to more than $1 billion in the century between 1860 and 1960. The personal papers of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., located in Record Group 2 (Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller) of the Rockefeller Family Archives, document Rockefeller's life and philanthropy. While the bulk of documentation in Record Group 2 concerns the establishment and operation of his philanthropies and businesses, these papers illuminate Rockefeller's education, family relationships, travels, and his religious and public life. They also contain the voluminous research files prepared by Rockefeller's biographer and long-time adviser, Raymond B. Fosdick, which bring together otherwise widely-dispersed sources.
Scope and Contents note
The Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller (OMR) materials document the increasing role assumed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in the management of Rockefeller affairs and amply document his business and philanthropic affairs. They also chronicle the entrance of JDR Jr.'s sons, John D. 3rd, Nelson A., Laurance S., Winthrop, and David, into the world of business, philanthropy, civic leadership, and politics as they joined the office.
This material contains correspondence, reports, pamphlets, memoranda, deeds, maps, contracts, reports, minutes, charters, certificates of incorporation, clippings, diaries, notebooks, calendars, and memorabilia.
There is a microfilm card index of personal and institutional names.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 02
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records include: FA310 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
FA312 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Business Interests
FA313 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Civic Interests
FA314 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Cultural Interests
FA315 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Economic Reform Interests
FA316 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Educational Interests
FA317 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services
FA318 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Homes
FA319 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests
FA320 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests
FA321 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Real Estate
FA322 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Maps and Memorabilia
FA323 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Religious Interests
FA324 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards
FA325 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare - General Files
FA326 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, World Affairs
FA327 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare - Youth Files
FA329 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Public Relations
FA333 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Costume Collection
FA334 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Media
FA336 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller
FA337 Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Abby Rockefeller Mauze
Philanthropy; Philanthropy -- New York (N.Y.); International relations; International education; Juvenile delinquency; International relations -- United States; Medical care; Maternal health services; Medical research; Medical education; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Charitable contributions; Charities -- Investments; Charities; Civic improvement; Child welfare; International economic relations; International cooperation; Political campaigns -- United States; Political science; Prohibition; Public health; Public health administration; Public policy; Philanthropy -- United States; Medical sciences; New York (N.Y.); New York (State); Parks -- New York (State); Performing arts; Public welfare; Religion; Religious institutions; Restoration and conservation; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Health insurance; Housing rehabilitation; Public relations; Urban policy; Urban renewal; World War I; World War II; Rockefeller family -- Art collections; State governments -- United States; Travel; United States; Art, Modern; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Economic development; Art; Business enterprises, Foreign; Capital investments; Arts; Business; Federal government -- United States; Family planning; Government policy; Folk art; Economics; Economic policy; Education -- United States; Education; Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial; Standard Oil Company; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller Brothers Fund; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller Foundation; Rockefeller University
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Correspondence, 1881-1961; 1; 10 Document Box(es)
  Arrangement note
  Subseries 1, Correspondence, is arranged in four sections: Personal Correspondence, Office Correspondence, Letterbooks, and Special Letter File. Within each section, letters are arranged alphabetically by correspondent or chronologically. The Letterbooks section is arranged by subject.
  Scope and Contents note
  Subseries 1, Correspondence, is comprised of four sections: Personal Correspondence; Office Correspondence; Letterbooks (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick), and Special Letter File.
  The Personal Correspondence section contains incoming and outgoing correspondence, arranged alphabeticaly by correspondent. Significant correspondents includes JDR, Sr. (1901-1936), Laura Spelman Rockefeller (1891-1915), and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (1901-1946).
  The correspondence between Abby and JDR, Jr. consists of carbon transcriptions of select letters; some letters were edited prior to being transcribed. It is believed that JDR, Jr. selected the letters for transcription and destroyed others. The letters reveal an intense devotion and interdependence between husband and wife.
  The correspondence between JDR, Jr. and his father spans the years 1901 to 1936 and provides an unbroken record of their daily communications. Senior's letters also appear in the Office Correspondence and Letterbooks sections of Subseries 1, and in Record Group 1 of the Rockefeller Family Archives, which is the papers of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  The letterbooks in this subseries were compiled by Fosdick during the research phase or his work on "John D. Rockefeller, Jr: A Portrait" (1956). They contain selections from JDR, Jr.'s correspondence. The letterbooks are arranged by subjects which correspond to the final chapter headings. Material related to the compilation of these letterbooks is located in Subseries 5, Biographical Works, together with information about the so-called "Nevins books," assembled by Senior's biographer, Allan Nevins.
  The Special Letter File section is arranged alphabeticaly by correspondent. Correspondents include Nelson W. Aldrich (1904-1910), Andrew Carnegie (1903-1914), Alexis Carrel (1914-1931), Winston Churchill (1909-1946), Henry C. Frick (1908-1919), Charles Evans Hughes (1916-1920), Charles A. Lindbergh (1928-1931), Ignace Jan Paderewski (1916), John Singer Sargent (1917), Woodrow Wilson (1903-1904), and Wendell L. Wilkie (1940). This file was created and maintained by JDR, Jr.'s office staff.
  - Personal Correspondence - Dashiell, Bessie, 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence - Keebler, A.M., 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1902-1905, 1906-1916, 1918-1946. Typewritten copies of these letters 1902-1946. Also one set typed copies of miscellaneous Family letters. Mention of McCormick and Prentice 1917 trusts.
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1901-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Calling Card Messages from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1906-1941, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1901-1909 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Subject Book A-Z used by Nevins and Raymond B. Fosdick. Chronological 1885-1914, 1915-1936. Copies of John D. Rockefeller, Laura Spelman Rockefeller letters 1856-1900.
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1901-1909 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1910-1930 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1891-1895 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Earliest letter - June 8, 1891. Weekly Sunday letters during school year in 1894 (1891-1894). Regular weekly letters from College, some Europe (1895-1896). Also 1 item from William A. Rockefeller and 4 from Eliza D. Rockefeller to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1891-1895 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Regular weekly letters from College, some Europe (1895-1896). Graduation, trip to Europe, start at office (1897-1899), Engagement, Work, Trust, Stewardship, Love, Children (1900-1914).
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1896-1915, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller Children, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Personal Correspondence - Rockefeller Children, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 0045A)
  - Personal Correspondence - Spelman, Lucy Henry, 1883-1896 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    November 6, 1883; December 23, 1883; January 29, 1884; July 22, 1887; December 2, 1887; January 24, 1888; February 29, 1888; September 9, 1889; February 28, 1892; January 28, 1894; March 1, 1894; January 28, 1895; March 1, 1895; January 28, 1896. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Grandmother: February 2, 1896 - Not the letter, but the spirit of the law.
  - Personal Correspondence - Strong, Augustus H., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Personal Correspondence - Strong Family, 1886-1937, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 48)
    Strong, Kate, 1886-1937, n.d. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, October 28, 1888. Visit to Rochester. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, December 3, 1888. Riding in the Park. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, April 8, 1888. Sightseeing interest. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, January 8, 1888. Skating, sleighing. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, August 16, 1886. Western trip. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Kate Strong, July 24, 1886. Kate Strong to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1901-1902, 1925.
    Strong, Margaret, 1904
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Office Correspondence, 1922-1943, 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Office Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Office Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Office Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Office Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Office Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Office Correspondence - Maple Sugar Purchases, 1942-1953 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s purchase of syrup and sugar.
  - Office Correspondence - R. Thomas Son, Ltd., 1928-1948 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    London shoe manufacture. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchased some shoes from them.
  - Letterbooks (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick) - Part I, 1884-1952 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also Box 58, folder 504.
  - Letterbooks (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick) - Part II, 1884-1952 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Letterbooks (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick) - Part III, 1884-1952 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Letterbooks (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick) - Part IV, 1884-1952 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Letterbook (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick), 1884-1952 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    Letter from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to John D. Rockefeller, Sr., October 2, 1931.
  - Letterbook (compiled by Raymond B. Fosdick), 1884-1952 (Box 7, Folder 0073A)
    Family correspondence between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and his children.
  - Special Letter File - Index to Letters (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Special Letter File (A), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    Collection of letters set aside by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as of particular significance.
  - Special Letter File (B), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Special Letter File (C), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Special Letter File - Carnegie, Andrew, 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Special Letter File (D), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Special Letter File - Dunbar, May H., 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Special Letter File (E), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Special Letter File (F), 1899-1953 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Special Letter File (G), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Special Letter File (H), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Special Letter File (I-J), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Special Letter File (K), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Special Letter File (L), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Special Letter File (M), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Special Letter File (N-O), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Special Letter File (P-Q), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Special Letter File (R), 1899-1953 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Not Used (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Special Letter File (S), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Special Letter File (T), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Special Letter File (U-V), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Special Letter File (W), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Special Letter File - War Letters (World War I), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Special Letter File (X-Z), 1899-1953 (Box 10, Folder 107)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Personal Papers, 1878-1960, 1974; 2; 35 Document Box(es)
  Subseries 2 is arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  Subseries 2, Personal Papers, includes a variety of memorabilia, among them JDR, Jr.'s piece of groom cake (1901), his Tiffany leather briefcase, playing cards and calling cards, an ink wiper, and two silver hinged photograph albums containing family portraits. There are also color photographs of Rockefeller's porcelain and pottery collections, arranged by disposition to dealers (Duveen, Parish-Watson, C.T. Roo) or museums (the Brooklyn Museum, Colonial Williamsburg, the Metropolitan Museum, Rhode Island School of Design). One folder contains photographs of the English, Italian, and Netherlandish furniture ordered in 1924 from Charles of London for Rockefeller's new offices at 26 Broadway.
  The meticulous record-keeping and accounting practices characteristic of Senior were passed on to his son. Subseries 2 contains early accounts (1884-1886) kept by Senior for his children and for his wife, Laura, as well as 22 volumes of JDR, Jr.'s daily expense notebooks (1889-1900).
  Reference and reference clippings files are organized according to such topics as "Helpful poems and verses sent me at the time of Abby's going," or "Miscellaneous helpful thoughts." Also present in Subseries 2 are JDR, Jr.'s surviving school papers, including essays, examinations, report cards, and lecture notes, arranged chronologically by school and thereunder alphabetically by type of material. Files document work done at the New York School of Languages, Douglas School, Cutler School, the Browning School, and Brown University.
  The travel records housed in Subseries 2 fill boxes 39 through 45. They are organized in two sections, foreign travel records and United States travel records. Thereunder, records are arranged chronologically by trip. These files reveal JDR, Jr.'s great curiosity about the world, his eagerness to share experience, and his desire to retain the best possible scholars and guides in the service of edification and enjoyment. In addition to keeping a diary, he saved railroad timetables, shipboard maps and menus, passenger lists, itineraries, and printed souvenirs. These items are often marked: "Hold for next trip." Files also record the thorough and dedicated activity of the family staff as they sought to reserve passage (usually for the family and several traveling companions) by train, ship, or car; book hotel accommodations; contact local travel agents; pay accumulated bills; research potential purchases; or wire messages home. Especially well recorded is the 1929 trip to Egypt, led by James Breasted of the Oriental Institute in Chicago. Correspondence describes the trip preparations, which involved ordering the proper hats and suits, based on Breasted's recommendations.
  To give themselves a rest and to introduce their children to the history and beauties of their homeland, the Rockefeller family made railroad and car trips to the western United States in 1920, 1924, 1926, and 1930. These trips are thoroughly documented by correspondence, diaries, itineraries, and souvenirs. Prior to his marriage in 1901, Rockefeller traveled frequently, and diaries exist for trips to Yellowstone Park (1886) and to California and Alaska (1899). Before parenthood intervened, he and Abby traveled to the Berkshires in 1904 and 1906.
  - Account Books - Bessie, Alta, Edith, John, 1884-1886, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Account Books - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1885, 1887-1889 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Account Books, 1889-1890 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Account Books, 1891-1893 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Account Books, 1893-1895 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Account Books, 1895-1898 (Box 11, Folder 113)
  - Account Books, 1895-1898 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Account Books, 1898-1900 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Account Books, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Account Books - Benevolent Accounts, 1898-1901 (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Account Books - Benevolent Accounts, 1899-1901 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Accounting Exercise Books, [1877?] (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Appointment Books, 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Appointment Books, 1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Appointment Books, 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Appointment Books, 1944-1946 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Appointment Books, 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Appointment Books, 1951-1954 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Appointment Books, 1955-1958 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Appointment Books, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Autograph Samples of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Signatures (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - Awards - Correspondence and Citations, 1935-1959 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    Declinations of awards. Acceptance of Greek Order of the Phoenix. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Awards - Keys, 1934-1935, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Birthday Files, 1930, 1937-1939, 1941-1942, 1944-1945, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    Letters, cards and wires of best wishes. Answers by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. as by his secretaries. Some press coverage of birthday. Many personally acknowledged by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Birthday Files, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Birthday Files, 1950-1953 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Birthday Files, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Birthday Files, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Birthday Files, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Birthday Files, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Birthday Files - Employees, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Birthday Files - Family, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Birthday Files - Employees, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Birthday Files - Family, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - Birthday Files - Friends, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Birthday Files - Friends, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Birthday Files - Employees, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Birthday Files - Family, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Birthday Files - Friends, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - Birthday Files - Friends, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - Book Collections - The Eyrie, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Book Collections - 4 West 54th Street, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Book Collections - Kykuit, 1937, 1956-1959 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - Book Collections - 740 Park Avenue Office, 1957-1961, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 151)